sportsmansparadiseonline.com 2019-12-09

# Privacy Policy | SPO

## Advertising Privacy Statement

This Site is affiliated with AdThrive, LLC (“AdThrive”) for the purposes of placing advertising on the Site.  AdThrive uses standard and widely-available tools for the placement and serving of ads, including those provided by Google, Inc. and its affiliates. We publish interest-based advertisements on the Site; that is, ads that are tailored to reflect your interests. To help understand your interests, AdThrive, Google and our other advertising partners will track your behaviour on our website and on other websites across the Internet using cookies.

A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. Cookies may be either “persistent” cookies or “session” cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.  Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

By using this Site, you consent to the use of such cookies and the sharing of data captured by such cookies with AdThrive, Google, and our other third party partners. You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/). You can also opt out of the network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative’s multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/). However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained.

For European Economic Area Residents

If you reside in a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), then under the GDPR and applicable data protection laws you have the rights, among other things, to access your personal data, have us erase it, and/or restrict its further processing.  If you wish to access or delete your personal data (if any) maintained by us or AdThrive related to advertising on the Site, you can contact us at  **info@sportsmansparadiseonline.com** and contact AdThrive at [info@adthrive.com](mailto:info@adthrive.com). If you wish to see a list of the advertising partners we work with or change which of those partners track your behavior using cookies, click the ad preferences link at the bottom of the site. (Available in the EU.)

 **Privacy Statement of Sportsman’s Paradise Online**

Statement No 52367

 **Information about our Organization and Web site**

Modern information and communication technologies play a fundamental role in the activities of an organisation like Sportsman’s Paradise Online . We are based in the USA .

 **Our principal activities are:** Web Content  
A Community of people who interact and converse about wildlife.

 **Our privacy policy covers Sportsman’s Paradise Online and its Web site:** Website Name: Sportsman’s Paradise Online  
Country: USA  
Controller: Webmaster  
Web Sites(s): https://sportsmansparadiseonline.com

 **Providing Visitors with Anonymous Access**

You can access our Web site home page and browse our site without disclosing your personal data.

 **The services and links of our Web site**

Our Web site enables you to communicate with other visitors or to post information to be accessed by others. When you do so, other visitors may collect the data you post or share. Comments made on our public commenting threads may be shared or viewed by anyone.

 **Our Web site also includes a link to:** Google Adsense – Google Affiliate Network  
Infolinks  
Viglink, Lijit, Amazon  
Such third party Web service providers may collect personal data about our visitors.

 **Automatic Collection of Information**

We do use cookies on our Web site. Cookies are used to help keep registered users logged in who utilize the “remember me” check box at login. Registered users who do not elect to click “remember me” at login will remain logged in for 4 hours or until they close their browser. This is achieved by the use of cookies.

We do not automatically log personal data about specific individuals(for example: your email). Any data collected has been manually input by the user.

 **Data Collection and Purpose Specification**

Regarding The  **General Data Protection Regulation**  ( **GDPR** ) (EU) 2016/679 effective 05/25/2018. Superseding the [Data Protection Directive](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_Protection_Directive "Data Protection Directive"), the regulation contains provisions and requirements pertaining to the processing of [personally identifiable information](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Personally_identifiable_information "Personally identifiable information") of data subjects inside the European Union. Business processes that handle personal data must be built with [privacy by design](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Privacy_by_design "Privacy by design") and by default, meaning that personal data must be stored using [pseudonymisation](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pseudonymisation "Pseudonymisation") or full [anonymisation](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_anonymization "Data anonymization"), and use the highest-possible privacy settings by default, so that the data is not available publicly without explicit consent, and cannot be used to identify a subject without additional information stored separately. No personal data may be processed unless it is done under a lawful basis specified by the regulation, or if the data controller or processor has received explicit, opt-in consent from the data’s owner. The business must allow this permission to be withdrawn at any time.

 **Privacy Compliance**

Sportsmansparadiseonline.com has been built with privacy by design using the highest stored data security available. Personal data is not available publicly with out explicit consent and cannot be used to identify a subject without additional information stored separately.

A direct link to this privacy policy is available on **every page** of sportsmansparadiseonline.com.

The goal of our privacy policy is to inform and empower the user via this privacy policy and give each user explicit access to the personal information they have provided. It’s each users choice as to what information they wish to make public. Each user account has the highest possible privacy settings by default. This setting can be changed if that user chooses to do so. The privacy settings are located in each user profile. Each user is in compete control of their data. Users are also able to delete their entire account including all personal data via their profile settings if they so choose.

When you create an account at sportsmansparadiseonline.com either via the registration form or through authorization via a social network(facebook,twitter,ect.) you are providing personal information. In doing so you are is consenting to have sportsmansparadiseonline.com store that data.

Comments posted in the comment threads found on sportsmansparadiseonline.com are not written or endorsed by Sportsman’s Paradise Online.

Comments posted in the comment threads found on sportsmansparadiseonline.com are viewable by the public.

 **Privacy Support**

If you have an enquiry or concern about our privacy policy, please contact:

 **Contact Information :**

Email address : info@sportsmansparadiseonline.com  
URL : https://sportsmansparadiseonline.com
